FAJAR PUTHUSSERI MADATHIL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I am a flexible and experienced software developer with excellent programming and management skills. I am determined and enthusiastic, I have developed good planning and organizational skills and am confident working independently or as part of a team.

Furthermore, I am an expert in handling multiple tasks competently and at working well under pressure. And I am proficient in both spoken and written **English**. My native country is India and currently working in Saudi Arabia as **Senior Software Developer.**

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

Nagel Express, Riyadh, KSA / December 2021 - Present

- Participated in project meetings with various departments to gather requirements.
- Implemented new modules in the existing .Net web application developed using Devexpress XAF framework.
- Developed 4 new mobile applications using Flutter framework.
- Developed a single page application using **Angular** CLI.

Software Programmer

Nabda Platinum Business Services, Jeddah, KSA / March 2015 – November 2021

- Worked with the team members to provide timely and accurate estimates for development modules.
- Designed and developed up to **9** web applications using **ASP.NET** MVC pattern as well as webforms.
- Implemented variety of UI designs mainly using frameworks like **Bootstrap.**
- DOM manipulation and webpage interaction with APIs are done using JavaScript library **jQuery** and AJAX.
- Web APIs are created using ASP.NET Web API 2 and ASMX frameworks.
- Created various database objects and involved in writing complex SQL scripts and scheduling Stored Procedures using SQL Jobs in MS SQL Server.
- Implemented various AWS services like **S3** and **Rekognition**.
- Interactive UIs are developed using **Angular** framework.
- Deployed and maintained multiple websites on the server using **IIS.**
- Version control systems **GIT** and **TFS** are used to manage the changes in the projects and keep them synced among the team.

Sample Project: You can refer the following URL where I have hosted a sample application which is developed using Angular framework.

menu.mesmerito.com

- fajarpm@gmail.com
- +966506127011
- 4105 Ibn As Sakit, Jarir, Riyadh.
- in linkedin.com/in/fajarmadathil-61a8b422

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C#, JavaScript, Typescript, Dart

Data Modeling

JSON, XML

Data Management

MS SQL, MySql

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Application

Rajagiri College of Social Sciences, Cochin, India 2010 - 2013

Bachelor of Computer Science

Garden City College, Bangalore, India 2006 - 2009